thesteadyhandblog.com 2019-03-07

# Privacy Policy | The Steady Hand

**Privacy Policy Dated: December 2018  
**

_(Psst…if you want me to delete any and all information that my website has collected from you please email me at aprile.mazey@gmail.com. If there is information on my site that you would like to talk to me about please email me at aprile.mazey@gmail.com. I had to write all this legal jargon but I would love to save you from reading it. Whatever it is, email me and I am sure we can work it out. Thanks!)_

The Steady Hand Blog is owned, operated, written and edited by Aprile Mazey. Our website address is: http://thesteadyhandblog.com. The Steady Hand is based out of Murfreesboro, TN USA.

For questions about The Steady Hand, please contact [**aprile@thesteadyhandblog.com**](mailto:aprile@thesteadyhandblog.com).

This policy explains the what, how, and why of the information I collect when you visit my website. It also explains the specific ways I use and disclose that information. I take your privacy extremely seriously and will never sell your information or email addresses. This Privacy Policy is effective with respect to any data that I have collected, or collect, about and/or from you, according to my Terms of Use.

 **Information I Collect**  
Information you voluntarily provide to me: When you sign up for my email newsletter, send me an email, comment on my blog posts, or communicate with me in any way, you are voluntarily giving me information that I collect. That information may include either your name, physical address, email address, IP address, phone number, as well as details including gender, occupation, location, and other demographic information. By giving me this information, you consent to this information being collected, used, disclosed, transferred to the United States and stored by me, as described in this Privacy Policy.

When you browse my Websites, I may collect information about your visit to my Websites, your usage of the Services, and your web browsing. That information may include your IP address, your operating system, your browser ID, your browsing activity, and other information about how you interacted with my Websites or other websites. I may collect this information as a part of log files as well as through the use of cookies or other tracking technologies. My use of cookies is discussed more below.

Any information you include in a comment on my blog may be read, collected, and used by anyone. If your Personal Information appears on my blog and you want it removed, contact me at aprile@thesteadyhandblog.com.

Comments  
When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

Media  
If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

Contact Form  
The contact form submission data — IP address, user agent, name, email address, website, and message — is submitted to the Akismet service (also owned by Automattic) for the sole purpose of spam checking. The actual submission data is stored in the database of the site on which it was submitted and is emailed directly to the owner of the form (i.e. me). This email will include the submitter’s IP address, timestamp, name, email address, website, and message.

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

 **Cookies and tracking:** I use cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer the website, track users’ movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about my user base as a whole. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. I partner with a third party to either display advertising on my website or to manage my advertising on other sites. My third party partner may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you advertising or other content based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising click [**http://preferences-mgr.truste.com**](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/)/ (or if located in the European Union click [**http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/**](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). Please note you might continue to receive generic ads. My use of cookies is discussed more below.

When you first visit this website we ask for your consent to use cookies. If you delete your cookies or clear your cache, you may be asked to give your consent again. This is because a cookie is usually used to remember the choice you made the first time.

If you wish to revoke your consent to the use of cookies on this website you can either delete the cookies in your browser’s memory or clear your cache.

If you wish to prevent cookies being set before you visit this website, or most other websites, you can set your browser to block cookies. Most browsers allow you to do this in their settings.

My Websites include social media features, such as the Facebook Like button. These features may collect information about your IP address and which page you are visiting on my Website, and they may set a cookie to make sure the feature functions properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third-party or hosted directly on my Website. I also maintain presences on social media platforms including Facebook, Pinterest, Google+, Twitter, and Instagram. Any information, communications, or materials you submit to me via a social media platform is done at your own risk without any expectation of privacy. I cannot control the actions of other users of these platforms or the actions of the platforms themselves. Your interactions with those features and platforms are governed by the privacy policies of the companies that provide them.

 **How I use collected information**  
The Steady Hand may collect and use Users personal information for the following purposes:  
– To improve customer service: Information you provide helps me respond to your customer service requests and support needs more efficiently.  
– To send periodic emails: I may use the email address you provide to respond to your inquiries, questions, and/or other requests. If a User decides to opt-in to my mailing list, they will receive emails that may include company news, updates, related product or service information, etc. If at any time the User would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, I include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

 **Sharing your personal information**  
I do not sell, trade, or rent Users personal identification information to others. I may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any personal identification information regarding visitors and users with my business partners, trusted affiliates and advertisers for the purposes outlined above. I may use third-party service providers to help me operate my business and the Site or administer activities on my behalf, such as sending out newsletters or surveys. I may share your information with these third parties for those limited purposes provided that you have given me your permission.

 **What Rights You Have Over Your Data**

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

 **Where We Send Your Data**

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

 **Third party websites**  
Users may find advertising or other content on my Site that link to the sites and services of my partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors and other third parties. I do not control the content or links that appear on these sites and are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from my Site. In addition, these sites or services, including their content and links, may be constantly changing. These sites and services may have their own privacy policies and customer service policies. Browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which have a link to our Site, is subject to that website’s own terms and policies. If you submit Personal Information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. I encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Website you visit.

 **Advertising**  
I may partner with third parties to display advertising on my Websites or to manage my advertising on other sites and may share Personal Information with them for this purpose. All third parties with which I share this information enter into a contract with me that requires them to use your Personal Information in a manner that is consistent with this policy. Ads appearing on my site may be delivered to Users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile non personal identification information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This privacy policy does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. My third party partners or I may use technologies, such as cookies, to gather information about your activities on our Websites and other sites in order to provide you with advertising based on your browsing activities and interests. My use of cookies is discussed more below.

 **Google Adsense**  
Some of the ads may be served by Google. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to Users based on their visit to my Site and other sites on the Internet. DART uses “non-personally identifiable information” and does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, etc. You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html>. For more information: [**How Google uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps**](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/partners/). You also have the option to [**Get Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on**](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

 **Notice of Breach of Security**  
If a security breach causes an unauthorized intrusion into my system that materially affects you then I will notify you as soon as possible and later report the action I took in response.

 **Safeguarding Your Information**  
I take reasonable and appropriate measures to protect Personal Information from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction, taking into account the risks involved in the processing and the nature of the Personal Information.

 **I Operate in the United States**  
My office is located in the United States. My website is hosted by Media Temple. Your information may be transferred to, stored, or processed in the United States. While the data protection, privacy, and other laws of the United States might not be as comprehensive as those in your country, I take many steps to protect your privacy. By using my Websites, you understand and consent to the collection, storage, processing, and transfer of your information to my facilities in the United States and those third parties with whom I share it as described in this policy.

 **Accuracy of Data, Transparency, and Choice**  
I do my best to keep your data accurate and up to date, to the extent that you provide me with the information I need to do so. If your data changes (for example, if you have a new email address), then you are responsible for notifying me of those changes. Upon request, I will provide you with information about whether I hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your Personal Information.

I will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as long as needed to provide you with my Services (email newsletters).

 **Changes to this privacy policy**  
The Steady Hand has the discretion to update this privacy policy at any time. When I do, I will revise the updated date at the top of this page. All updates and amendments are effective immediately upon notice, which I may give by any means, including, but not limited to, by posting a revised version of this Privacy Policy or other notice on the Website. I encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how I am helping to protect the personal information I collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of modifications.

 **Your acceptance of these terms**  
By using this Site, you signify your acceptance of this policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use my Site. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.

 **Contacting me**  
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please contact me at: aprile@thesteadyhandblog.com

 **DISCLOSURE POLICY**  
This Disclosure Policy is valid from March 29, 2011.

The FTC requires bloggers to disclose any type of advertising revenue received from my blog. As such, please note I make money from the banner ads on my header, sidebar, posts and footer.

AprileMazey/The Steady Hand participates in Affiliate marketing programs for IZEA, Smile Brilliant, Krochet Kids, Leisure Arts, USA Dawgs, Inc., Crescent Health Center/Ageless Derma, Purely Alpaca, White Plum, Nectar Clothing, Creativebug, Magic Murals, Business2Blogger, Luna Bazaar, Glik’s, Craftsy, Imagine Toys, eShakti, Sun Diego Boardshops, Surf Fanatics and Shareasale. Any links to those sites may earn advertising fees.

Aprile Mazey is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon.com.

The Steady Hand accepts forms of cash advertising, sponsorship, paid insertions or other forms of compensation. The compensation received will never influence the content, topics or posts made in this blog. All advertising is in the form of advertisements generated by a third-party ad network. Those advertisements will be identified as paid advertisements.

The Steady Hand is compensated to provide opinion on products, services, websites and various other topics. Even though I receive compensation for my posts or advertisements, I always give my honest opinions, findings, beliefs, or experiences on those topics or products. The views and opinions expressed on this blog are purely my own. Any product claim, statistic, quote or other representation about a product or service should be verified with the manufacturer, provider or party in question.

The Steady Hand does not contain any content which might present a conflict of interest.

 **Cookie Statement**

This Cookie Statement explains how The Steady Hand (“ **The Steady Hand** ”, “ **I** “, “ **me** “, and “ **mine** “) use cookies and similar technologies to recognize you when you visit http://www.thesteadyhandblog.com or any website owned, operated or controlled by us (“ **Websites** “). It explains what these technologies are and why we use them, as well as your rights to control my use of them.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

 **What are cookies?**  
Cookies are small data files that are placed on your computer or mobile device when you visit a website. Cookies are widely used by website owners in order to make their websites work, or to work more efficiently, as well as to provide reporting information.

Cookies set by the website owner (in this case, The Steady Hand) are called “first party cookies”. Cookies set by parties other than the website owner are called “third party cookies”. Third party cookies enable third party features or functionality to be provided on or through the website (e.g. like advertising, interactive content and analytics). The parties that set these third party cookies can recognize your computer both when it visits the website in question and also when it visits certain other websites.

 **Why do I use cookies?**  
I use first party and third party cookies for several reasons. Some cookies are required for technical reasons in order for my Websites to operate, and I refer to these as “essential” or “strictly necessary” cookies. Other cookies also enable me to track and target the interests of my users to enhance the experience on my Websites. Third parties serve cookies through my Websites for advertising, analytics and other purposes. What about other tracking technologies, like web beacons?

Cookies are not the only way to recognise or track visitors to a website. We and our third party partners may use other, similar technologies from time to time, like web beacons (sometimes called “tracking pixels” or “clear gifs”). These are tiny graphics files that contain a unique identifier that enable us to recognise when someone has visited our Websites or opened an e-mail that we have sent them. This allows us, for example, to monitor the traffic patterns of users from one page within our Websites to another, to deliver or communicate with cookies, to understand whether you have come to our Websites from an online advertisement displayed on a third-party website, to improve site performance, and to measure the success of e-mail marketing campaigns. In many instances, these technologies are reliant on cookies to function properly, and so declining cookies will impair their functioning.

 **How can I control cookies?**  
You have the right to decide whether to accept or reject cookies.

You can set or amend your web browser controls to accept or refuse cookies. If you choose to reject cookies, you may still use my website though your access to some functionality and areas of my website may be restricted. As the means by which you can refuse cookies through your web browser controls vary from browser-to-browser, you should visit your browser’s help menu for more information.

When you first visit this website we ask for your consent to use cookies. If you delete your cookies or clear your cache, you may be asked to give your consent again. This is because a cookie is usually used to remember the choice you made the first time.

If you wish to revoke your consent to the use of cookies on this website you can either delete the cookies in your browser’s memory or clear your cache.

If you wish to prevent cookies being set before you visit this website, or most other websites, you can set your browser to block cookies. Most browsers allow you to do this in their settings.

 **How often will you update this Cookie Statement?**  
I may update this Cookie Statement from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to the cookies I use or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons. Please therefore re-visit this Cookie Statement regularly to stay informed about my use of cookies and related technologies.

The date at the top of this page indicates when it was last updated.

 **Where can I get further information?**  
If you have any questions about my use of cookies or other technologies, please email me at aprile@thesteadyhandblog.com.

 **COPYRIGHT**  
All content on www.thesteadyhandblog.com is the sole property of the site, unless otherwise specified. All Rights Reserved.

 **Contact**

The Steady Hand  
Aprile Mazey  
aprile@thesteadyhandblog.com  
aprile.mazey@gmail.com

For more contact information please email me. Thank you!
